A Finding Aid to the Henry Varnum Poor Papers, 1873-2001, bulk 1904-1970, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Artwork, circa 1890s-circa 1961; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 3.5 Linear feet Boxes 4-6, 9-10, OV 19-22
  - By Henry Varnum Poor, circa 1890s-circa 1961; 5.1; Archival Resource Key
    - Sketchbooks, Archival Resource Key
      - Sketchbook 5, circa 1924-1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 19)
        Sketch of Wharton Esherick plate
      - Sketchbook 6, 1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 20)
        Notes on pottery glazes
      - Sketchbook 7, circa 1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 21)
        "Pottery/Sketches/Peter in Hat"
      - Sketchbook 8, circa 1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Sketchbooks 9 and 10, circa 1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Sketchbook 11, circa 1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 24)
        Pottery sketches and notes
      - Sketchbooks 12 and 13, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 25)
        Southwest Sicily and notes on art seen in Italy
      - Sketchbook 14, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 26)
        "Pitigliano/Grotto di Castri"
      - Sketchbook 15, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 27)
        Colorado Springs, and "Gedney and Dominick" (contains a few 19th century drawings)
      - Sketchbook 16, circa 1937-1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 28)
        Interior Department mural and statement regarding art
      - Sketchbook 17, circa 1938-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 29)
        Penn State mural
      - Sketchbook 18, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 30)
        The Scarlet Letter illustrations
      - Sketchbooks 19 and 20, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 31)
        Alaska
      - Sketchbook 21, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Sketchbook 22, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Sketchbook 23, 1946 or later; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Sketchbook 24, circa 1946-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)
        Studio sketch class and State College drawings
      - Sketchbook 25, 1957[?]; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Sketchbook 26, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 5)
        Journal entry dated Aug. 18, 1962
      - Sketchbook 27 and 28, 1964-1965 and circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 6)
        Early Truro and Florida
      - Sketchbooks 29, 30, and 31, circa 1900-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 7)
        Notes, pottery sketches, and lists
      - Sketchbooks 32 and 33, circa 1900-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 8)
        Pottery sketches, notes, and biographical notes
      - Sketchbooks 34 and 35, circa 1900-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Sketchbooks 36 and 37, circa 1900-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Sketchbooks 38 and 39, circa 1900-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Sketchbook 40, circa 1900-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Sketchbook 41, circa 1900-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Sketchbook 42, circa 1900-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Sketchbook 43, circa 1900-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Sketchbook 44, circa 1900-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Sketchbook 45, circa 1900-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Watercolors, circa 1920-circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 18)
      Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folder 12
    - Oversized Artwork by Poor scanned with Box 4, Folders 2-4, 6, 11-21, 30-39, 1918-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1-10)
    - Oversized Artwork by Poor scanned with Box 4, Folders 23-26, Box 5, Folders 1-12, 15-16, and Box 6, Folder 18, 1918-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1-12)
    - Oversized Artwork by Poor scanned with Box 4, Folder 11, circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 19)
    - Oversized Artwork by Poor scanned with Box 4, Folders 30-37, circa 1918-1943; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 20)
    - Oversized Artwork by Poor scanned with Box 4, Folder 40, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 21)
    - Oversized Artwork by Poor scanned with Box 5, Folder 16, 1918-1919; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 22)
  - By Other Artists, circa 1938-circa 1949; 5.2; Archival Resource Key
    The other artists represented in this subseries are Anne Poor and Ernest Watson.
    - Artwork by Ernest Watson and Anne Poor, circa 1938-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 19)
      Drawings by: Anne Poor of Henry Varnum Poor's Hands for the Lincoln Figure in The Land Grant Frescoes, Pennsylvania State College; and by Ernest Watson, sketch of Crow House interior. Oversized material housed in Box 10, Folder 13.
    - Oversized Artwork by Anne Poor scanned with Box 6, Folder 19, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Architectural Projects, circa 1940-1966; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.7 Linear feet Box 6, OV 24-26, RD 14-17
  Found are drawings and architectural prints documenting houses designed and built by Poor, including his own studio. Other projects include the homes of Jules Billig, Milton Caniff, MacDonald Deming, Burgess Meredith, Bessie B. Poor, Isobel Prado, John Houseman, and Elizabeth S. Sargent. Researchers should note that photographs of architectural projects may be found within the photographs series (Series 9).
  This series has been partially scanned. Rolled documents of architectural prints have not been scanned due to the fragile nature of the document.
  - Milton Canniff and Bessie B. Poor houses, and Unidentified, circa 1940-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 20)
    Oversized material housed in OV 24-26
  - Jules Billig House, circa 1966; Archival Resource Key (Roll 14)
  - MacDonald Deming House, circa 1959; Archival Resource Key (Roll 15)
  - Burgess Meredith House, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Roll 16)
  - Isobel Prado, John Houseman, Elizabeth S. Sargent houses and Henry Varnum Poor Studio, circa 1941-1957; Archival Resource Key (Roll 17)
  - Oversized Architectural Drawings scanned with Box 6, Folder 20, circa 1941-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 24)
  - Oversized Architectural Drawings scanned with Box 6, Folder 20, circa 1941-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 25)
  - Oversized Architectural Drawings scanned with Box 6, Folder 20, circa 1941-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 26)
- Miscellaneous Records, 1882-1967; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet Boxes 6, 11, FC 30-31
  Family memorabilia consists of the autograph book belonging to Josie Graham Poor, a stored wheat account sheet from the Poor Elevator business, and two motion picture reels. Researchers should note that the script of the film Painting a True Fresco is among Poor's writings (Series 3).
  This series has been partially scanned.
  - Family Memorabilia, 1882; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Guest Book Pages (unidentified events), 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - "The Land Grant Murals at Pennsylvania State College", circa 1962; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 31)
  - "Painting a True Fresco", circa 1952; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 30)
- Printed Material, 1881-2001; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 1.2 Linear feet Boxes 6-7, 11, OV 27-29
  Family history includes the Poor-Poore Family Reunion, a publication containing significant background information. Among the travel souvenirs are a few items that may have been saved by his mother from their 1911 trip to Europe together.
  Also included are a copy of Jack London's The Call of the Wild illustrated by Poor, reproductions of illustrations for An Artist Sees Alaska and Ethan Frome, and two Associated American Artists greeting cards reproducing work by Poor.
  This series has been partially scanned. In some cases, exhibition catalogs and other publications have had their covers, title pages, and relevant pages scanned.
  - Articles, Archival Resource Key
    - About and/or Mentioning Henry Varnum Poor, 1913-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 23-25)
    - About and/or Mentioning Henry Varnum Poor, 1960-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 26-27)
    - About and/or Mentioning Henry Varnum Poor, 1980-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 28-29)
    - Henry Varnum Poor's House (includes "My Kitchen" by Bessie Breuer), 1925-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 30-31)
    - Art Topics, 1938-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous Subjects (not art-related), 1942-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Book Reviews, Archival Resource Key
    - An Artist Sees Alaska by Henry Varnum Poor (with advertisement), 1945-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - A Book of Pottery by Henry Varnum Poor, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Book, The Call of the Wild by Jack London, illustrated by Henry Varnum Poor, Limited Editions Club, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Books, Pottery Reference Books used by Henry Varnum Poor, Archival Resource Key
    - Barber, Edwin Atlee. Lead Glazed Pottery: Part First Common Clay, 1907; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Binns, Charles F. The Potter's Craft, 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Cox, George F. Pottery for Artists, Craftsmen and Teachers, 1914; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Searle, Alfred B. Kilns and Kilnbuilding, 1916; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Catalogs of Kilns, circa 1900; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Archival Resource Key
    - Henry Varnum Poor Solo and Group Shows, 1912-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 9-10)
    - Henry Varnum Poor Solo and Group Shows, 1961-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
    - Henry Varnum Poor Solo and Group Showsv, circa 1912-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Other Artists, circa 1940s-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 14-15)
  - Family History, 1881-1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Maps, Archival Resource Key
    - Anson Quadrangle, Somerset County, Maine, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 17)
      Oversized material housed in Box 11, Folder 2
    - Clarkstown, N.Y., showing Poor property, circa 1927-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 18)
      Oversized material housed in OV 27
  - Miscellaneous Printed Items, Archival Resource Key
    - Book Announcement, Brochures, Menu, circa 1910s-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Mentioning and/or Belonging to Mrs. A. J. Poor, 1910-1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Portfolio, Ceramic Art in America, edited by Richard B. Peterson, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 21)
    Oversized material housed in Box 11, Folder 3
  - Posters illustrated by V. Prouvé, 1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 22)
    Oversized material housed in OV 29
  - Reproductions of Work by Henry Varnum Poor, Archival Resource Key
    - American Artists Group Greeting Cards and Other Reproductions, circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 23)
      Oversized material housed in Box 11, Folders 4-6
    - Illustrations, An Artist Sees Alaska (proofs), circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 24)
      Oversized material housed in OV 28
    - The Call of the Wild, circa 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Ethan Frome, circa 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Life Article on Alaska, circa 1944-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 27)
      Oversized material housed in Box 11, Folder 4
    - The Scarlet Letter, circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 28)
      Oversized material housed in Box 11, Folder 5
    - Reproductions of Illustrations by Henry Varnum Poor ( An Artist Sees Alaska and Call of the Wild), 1944-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 29)
      Oversized material housed in Box 11, Folder 6
  - Theater Program from Pennsylvania State College production of Poor Mr. Varnum, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Travel Souvenirs, 1910-1916; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Oversized Printed Material scanned with Box 7, Folders 17, 21, 23, 27-29, 1941-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 2-6)
  - Oversized Printed Material scanned with Box 7, Folder 18, circa 1927-1967; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 27)
  - Oversized Printed Material scanned with Box 7, Folders 24-25, circa 1961; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 28)
  - Oversized Printed Material scanned with Box 7, Folder 22, 1917; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 29)
- Photographs, 1893-1984; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 2.3 Linear feet Boxes 7-8, 12-13
  Photographs record exterior and interior views of Henry Varnum Poor's architectural work, artwork by Poor and others, people, places, and miscellaneous subjects. This series also contains negatives, slides, and color transparencies.
  The series is arranged as 6 subseries.
  9.1: Architectural Work, 1966
  9.2: Artwork, circa 1908-1948
  9.3: People, 1893-1967
  9.4: Places, circa 1906-1943
  9.5: Miscellanesou Subjects, 1946-1984
  9.6: Negatives, Slides, and Transparencies, circa 1938-1975
  This series has been partially scanned. Negatives, slides, and transparencies have not been scanned.
  - Architectural Work, 1966; 9.1; Archival Resource Key
    Among the photographs of architectural work are views of Poor at the building sites of the Jules Billig and Milton Caniff houses. Many views of Poor's own home, Crow House, show the original portion under construction as well as a later addition; also included are views of the grounds and outbuildings such as Poor's new studio, workroom, and garage.
    Arranged alphabetically by family name.
    Among the photographs of people (Series 8.3) are views of Poor with others at Crow House that show exterior and interior details.
    - Maxwell Anderson House, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 32)
      Oversized material housed in Box 12, Folder 1
    - Jules Billig House, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 33)
      Oversized material housed in Box 12, Folder 2
    - Milton Caniff House, circa 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 34)
      Oversized material housed in Box 12, Folder 3
    - MacDonald Deming House, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 35)
      Oversized material housed in Box 12, Folder 4
    - Ben Hecht Poker Room, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - John Houseman House, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 37)
      Oversized material housed in Box 12, Folder 5
    - Burgess Meredith House and Bathing Pavilion, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Henry Varnum Poor House (Crow House), Archival Resource Key
      - Construction, 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 39-40)
        Oversized material housed in Box 12, Folder 7
      - Exterior, Some by Marjorie Content Toomer, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 41-42)
        Oversized material housed in Box 12, Folder 8
      - Exterior of House and Interior of Studio and Pottery, Ed McCarthy, photographer, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 43)
      - Interior, 1973; circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 44-45)
        All 1973 photographs by Ed Hausner of living and dining rooms include Anne Poor. Oversized material housed in Box 12, Folder 9
      - Garden, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 46)
      - Garage, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 47)
      - Pottery Interior, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 48)
      - Studio [new], Exterior, 1957 or later; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 49)
      - Studio [new], Interior, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 50)
      - Studio [old], Interior, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 51)
      - Work Room, Marjorie Content Toomer, photographer, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Various Projects, Multiple Location, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Oversized Photographs of Architectural Work scanned with Box 7, Folders 32-35, 37, 39-42, 44-46, 49-50, 53, 1920-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 1-13)
  - Artwork, circa 1908-1948; 9.2; Archival Resource Key
    Photographs of Poor's artwork include drawings and sketches, murals, paintings, pottery and ceramics. Also among the photographs of works of art are pieces by Willard W. Cummings, Wharton Esherick, unidentified artists, and pottery from the collections of the American Museum of Natural History and the Metropolitan Museum of Art (possibly research material for A Book of Pottery by Henry Varnum Poor).
    Among the photographs of architectural work are views of Poor at the building sites of the Jules Billig and Milton Caniff houses. Many views of Crow House show the original portion under construction, as well as a later addition; also included are views of the grounds and outbuildings such as Poor's new studio, workroom, and garage. Some Crow House photographs are by Marjorie Content Toomer.
    Images of Poor's artwork are arranged by medium and subject.
    - By Henry Varnum Poor, Drawings, Archival Resource Key
      - Figures, 1911; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 54)
      - Landscapes, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 55)
      - Mural Studies for Pennsylvania State College Land Grant Frescoes and Unidentified Ceramic Tile Mural, 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 56)
      - Portraits, circa 1918-1919; 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - By Henry Varnum Poor, Murals (fresco), Archival Resource Key
      - Department of the Interior, circa 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 58)
      - Department of Justice, circa 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 59)
      - Louisville Courier-Journal, circa 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 60)
        Oversized material housed in Box 13, Folder 3
      - Pennsylvania State College, The Land Grant Frescoes, circa 1940-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - By Henry Varnum Poor, Murals (ceramic), Archival Resource Key
      - Fresno Post Office and Court House, circa 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 62)
      - Klingenstein Pavilion, Mount Sinai Hospital, New York City, circa 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 63)
      - Unidentified, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - By Henry Varnum Poor, Paintings, Archival Resource Key
      - Figures, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 65-66)
      - Landscapes, circa 1908-1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 67)
      - Portraits, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 68-69)
      - Self-Portraits, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 70)
      - Still Life, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - By Henry Varnum Poor, Pottery and Ceramics, Archival Resource Key
      - Figures, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Fountain (Leda and the Swan for Helen Hayes and Charles McArthur), circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 2)
        Oversized material housed in Box 13, Folder 2
      - Heads, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous Objects, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Plates, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Plates and Other Objects, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Tile Screen for Abraham Lincoln High School Auditorium, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 7)
        Oversized material housed in Box 13, Folder 1
      - Tiles, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Vessels, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - By Other Artists, Archival Resource Key
      - Cummings, Willard W., 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Esherick, Wharton, circa 1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Pottery from the collections of American Museum of Natural History and Metropolitan Museum of Art (for A Book of Pottery by Henry Varnum Poor?), circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Unidentified, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Oversized Photographs of Artwork scanned with Box 7, Folder 60 and Box 8, Folders 2, 7, 1948-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 1-3)
  - People, circa 1893-1967; 9.3; Archival Resource Key
    Pictures of people include portraits and informal views of Henry Varnum Poor, Poor at work, and making a life mask. Among the views of Poor are several by photographer Marjorie Content Toomer, including one of the artist's hands holding brushes and a palette. Other photogaphs are of Poor with friends, clients, juries, students, various groups, and family members. Photographs of individuals include friends, immediate family, and various relatives.
    - Henry Varnum Poor Portraits, Archival Resource Key
      - Henry Varnum Poor, circa 1905-1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 14-15)
      - Henry Varnum Poor in World War II, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Henry Varnum Poor, circa 1940s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 17-18)
        Oversized material housed in Box 13, Folder 4
      - Henry Varnum Poor (Marjorie Content Toomer, photographer), circa 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Henry Varnum Poor at Work, Archival Resource Key
      - In the Pottery, circa 1940s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Making a Life Mask, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Painting, circa 1910s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - Painting Murals, Department of the Interior (with Anne Poor), 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Painting Murals, Pennsylvania State College, circa 1940-1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 24)
        Oversized material housed in Box 13, Folder 5
    - Henry Varnum Poor with Others, Archival Resource Key
      - Alaska (with M. R. ("Muktuk") Marston and Alaskans; aboard the Ada), 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - California, circa 1908-1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 26)
      - Clients (representative of Rockefeller Center, Mr. Billig, unidentified woman), circa 1933; circa 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Friends (including Milton Caniff, Marcel Duchamp, Wharton Esherick, Burgess Meredith, and unidentified), circa 1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 28)
      Oversized material housed in Box 13, Folder 6
    - Groups (high school class, Académie Julian [?], Town and Country dinner), 1905-circa 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Juries (Art Institute of Chicago, Carnegie Institute, Syracuse Museum of Fine Arts, and unidentified), 1935-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Parties at Crow House, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Students (Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center and unidentified), 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Students with Poor's Ceramic Tile Mural at Unidentified School, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Henry Varnum Poor with Family, Archival Resource Key
      - Sister, Mother and Other Relatives, circa 1893-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 34)